Sometimes people talk about support
人们有时将支持向量机
vector machines, as large margin
看做是大间距分类器
classifiers, in this video I'd
在这一部分
like to tell you what that
我将介绍其中的含义
means, and this will
这有助于我们
also give us a useful
直观理解
picture of what an SVM
SVM模型的
hypothesis may look like.
假设是什么样的
Here's my cost function for the support vector machine
这是我的支持向量机模型的代价函数
where here on the left
在左边这里
I've plotted my cost 1
我画出了关于 z 的代价函数 cost1(z)
of z function that I used for positive examples and on the right I've  plotted my
此函数用于正样本 而在右边这里我画出了
zero of 'Z' function, where I have
关于 z 的代价函数 cost0(z)
'Z' here on the horizontal axis.
横轴表示 z
Now, let's think about what
现在让我们考虑一下
it takes to make these cost functions small.
最小化这些代价函数的必要条件是什么
If you have a positive example,
如果你有一个正样本
so if y is equal to
y等于1
1, then cost 1 of
则只有在 z 大于等于1时
Z is zero only when
代价函数 cost1(z)
Z is greater than or equal to 1.
才等于0
So in other words, if you
换句话说
have a positive example, we really
如果你有一个正样本
want theta transpose x to be greater
我们会希望 θ 转置乘以 x
than or equal to 1
大于等于1
and conversely if y is
反之
equal to zero, look this
如果 y 是等于0的
cost zero of z function,
我们观察一下
then it's only in
函数cost0(z)
this region where z is
它只有在
less than equal to 1
z小于等于1
we have the cost is zero
的区间里
as z is equals to zero,
函数值为0
and this is an interesting property of the support
这是支持向量机的
vector machine right, which is
一个有趣性质 不是么
that, if you have a positive
事实上
example so if y is equal to one,
如果你有一个正样本 y等于1
then all we really need
则其实我们仅仅要求
is that theta transpose x is greater than equal to zero.
θ 转置乘以 x 大于等于0
And that would mean that we classify correctly
就能将该样本恰当分出
because if theta transpose x is greater than zero our
这是因为如果 θ 转置乘以 x 比0大的话
hypothesis will predict zero.
我们的模型代价函数值为0
And similarly, if you have
类似地 如果你有一个负样本
a negative example, then really all you want is that theta transpose x is
则仅需要 θ 转置乘以x
less than zero and that will make sure we got the example right.
小于等于0 就会将负例正确分离
But the support vector machine wants a bit more than that.
但是 支持向量机的要求更高
It says, you know, don't just barely get the example right.
不仅仅要能正确分开输入的样本
So then don't just
即不仅仅
have it just a little bit bigger than zero. What
要求 θ 转置乘以 x 大于0
i really want is for this to be
我们需要的是
quite a lot bigger than zero
比0值大很多
say maybe
比如
bit greater or equal to one
大于等于1
and I want this to be much less than zero.
我也想这个比0小很多
Maybe I want it less than or
比如我希望它
equal to -1.
小于等于-1
And so this builds in an
这就相当于在支持向量机中嵌入了
extra safety factor or safety
一个额外的安全因子
margin factor into the support vector machine.
或者说安全的间距因子
Logistic regression
当然 逻辑回归
does something similar too of course,
做了类似的事情
but let's see what
但是让我们看一下
happens or let's see what
在支持向量机中
the consequences of this are, in the
这个因子会
context of the support vector machine.
导致什么结果
Concretely, what I'd like to do next is
具体而言 我接下来
consider a case
会考虑一个特例
case where we set
我们将这个常数 C
this constant C to be
设置成
a very large value, so let's
一个非常大的值
imagine we set C to
比如我们假设
a very large value, may be a hundred thousand, some huge number.
C的值为100000 或者其它非常大的数
Let's see what the support vector machine will do.
然后来观察支持向量机会给出什么结果
If C is very,
如果 C 非常大
very large, then when minimizing
则最小化代价函数的时候
this optimization objective, we're going
我们将会很希望
to be highly motivated to choose
找到一个
a value, so that this
使第一项为0的
first term is equal to zero.
最优解
So let's try to
因此
understand the optimization problem in
让我们
the context of, what would
尝试在
it take to make this
代价项的第一项
first term in the objective
为0的情形下理解
equal to zero, because you
该优化问题
know, maybe we'll set C to
比如我们可以把 C
some huge constant, and this
设置成了非常大的常数
will hope, this should give us
这将给我们
additional intuition about what
一些关于支持向量机
sort of hypotheses a support vector machine learns.
模型的直观感受
So we saw already that
我们已经看到
whenever you have a training
输入一个训练样本
example with a label
标签为
of y=1 if you
y=1
want to make that first term
你想令第一项为0
zero, what you need is
你需要做的是
is to find a value of theta
找到一个 θ
so that theta transpose x i is greater
使得 θ 转置乘以 x
than or equal to 1.
大于等于1
And similarly, whenever we have an example,
类似地 对于一个训练样本
with label zero, in order
标签为 y=0
to make sure that the cost,
为了使
cost zero of Z,  in order to
cost0(z) 函数
make sure that cost is
这个函数
zero we need that theta transpose x i
值为0 我们需要 θ 转置
is less than or
乘以x 的值
equal to -1.
小于等于-1
So, if we think
因此
of our optimization problem as
现在考虑我们的优化问题
now, really choosing parameters
选择参数
and show that this first
使得第一项
term is equal to zero,
等于0
what we're left with is
就会导致下面的
the following optimization problem.
优化问题
We're going to minimize that first
因为我们将
term zero, so C
选择参数使第一项为0
times zero, because we're going
因此这个函数的第一项为0
to choose parameters so that's equal
因此是 C 乘以0
to zero, plus one half
加上二分之一
and then you know that
乘以第二项
second term and this
这里第一项
first term is 'C' times zero,
是C乘以0
so let's just cross that
因此可以将其删去
out because I know that's going to be zero.
因为我知道它是0
And this will be subject to the constraint
这将遵从以下的约束
that theta transpose x(i)
θ 转置乘以 x(i)
is greater than or equal to
大于或等于0.5
one, if y(i)
如果 y (i)
Is equal to one and
是等于1 的
theta transpose x(i) is less than
θ 转置乘以x(i)
or equal to minus one
小于等于-1
whenever you have
如果样本i是
a negative example and it
一个负样本
turns out that when you
这样 当你
solve this optimization problem, when you
求解这个优化问题的时候
minimize this as a function of the parameters theta
当你最小化这个关于变量 θ 的函数的时候
you get a very interesting decision
你会得到一个非常有趣的决策边界
boundary. Concretely, if you
具体而言
look at a data set
如果你考察
like this with positive and negative examples,  this data
这样一个数据集 其中有正样本 也有负样本
is linearly separable and by
可以看到 这个数据集是线性可分的
that, I mean that there exists, you know, a straight line,
我的意思是 存在一条直线把正负样本分开
altough there is many a different straight lines,
当然有多条不同的直线
they can separate the positive and
可以把
negative examples perfectly.
正样本和负样本完全分开
For example, here is one decision boundary
比如 这就是一个决策边界
that separates the positive and
可以把正样本
negative examples, but somehow that
和负样本分开
doesn't look like a very
但是多多少少这个
natural one, right? Or by
看起来并不是非常自然 是么?
drawing an even worse one, you know
或者我们可以画一条更差的决策界
here's another decision boundary that
这是另一条决策边界
separates the positive and negative examples
可以将正样本和负样本分开
but just barely.
但仅仅是勉强分开
But neither of those seem like particularly good choices.
这些决策边界看起来都不是特别好的选择
The Support Vector Machines will instead choose this
支持向量机将会选择
decision boundary, which I'm drawing in black.
这个黑色的决策边界
And that seems like a much better decision boundary
相较于之前
than either of
我用粉色或者绿色
the ones that I drew in magenta or in green.
画的决策界 这条黑色的看起来好得多
The black line seems like a more
黑线看起来
robust separator, it does
是更稳健的决策界
a better job of separating the positive and negative examples.
在分离正样本和负样本上它显得的更好
And mathematically, what that does is,
数学上来讲 这是什么意思呢
this black decision boundary has a larger distance.
这条黑线有更大的距离
That distance is called the margin, when I
这个距离叫做间距 (margin)
draw up this two extra
当画出这两条
blue lines, we see
额外的蓝线
that the black decision boundary has
我们看到黑色的决策界
some larger minimum distance from any of my training examples,
和训练样本之间有更大的最短距离
whereas the magenta and the green lines
然而粉线和蓝线
they come awfully close to the training examples.
离训练样本就非常近
and then that seems to do a less a good job separating
在分离样本的时候就会
the positive and negative classes than my black line.
比黑线表现差
And so
因此这张图片本身就有一定的误导性
this distance is called
这个距离叫做
the margin of the
支持向量机的
support vector machine and this
间距
gives the SVM a certain
而这是支持向量机
robustness, because it tries
具有鲁棒性的原因
to separate the data with as
因为它努力
a large a margin as possible.
用一个最大间距来分离样本
So the support vector machine is
因此支持向量机
sometimes also called a large
有时被称为
margin classifier and this
大间距分类器
is actually a consequence of
而这其实是
the optimization problem we wrote down on the previous slide.
求解上一页幻灯片上优化问题的结果
I know that you might be
我知道你也许
wondering how is it that
想知道
the optimization problem I wrote
求解上一页幻灯片中的优化问题
down in the previous slide, how
为什么会产生这个结果
does that lead to this large margin classifier.
它是如何产生这个大间距分类器的呢
I know I haven't explained that yet.
我知道我还没有解释这一点
And in the next video
在下一节视频中
I'm going to sketch a
我将会从直观上
little bit of the intuition about why
略述 为什么
that optimization problem gives us
这个优化问题
this large margin classifier. But
会产生大间距分类器
this is a useful feature to
总之这个图示
keep in mind if you are
有助于你
trying to understand what are the
理解
sorts of hypothesis that an SVM will choose.
支持向量机模型的做法
That is, trying to separate the
即努力将正样本和负样本
positive and negative examples with as big a margin as possible.
用最大的间距分开
I want to say one last thing
在本节课中
about large margin classifiers in
关于大间距分类器
this intuition, so we
我想讲最后一点
wrote out this large margin classification
我们将这个大间距分类器
setting in the case
中的正则化因子
of when C, that regularization concept,
常数C
was very large, I think
设置的非常大
I set that to a hundred thousand or something.
我记得我将其设置为了100000
So given a dataset
因此对这样的一个数据集
like this, maybe we'll choose
也许我们将选择
that decision boundary that
这样的决策界从而最大间距地
separate the positive and negative examples on large margin.
分离开正样本和负样本
Now, the SVM is actually sligthly
事实上 支持向量机现在
more sophisticated than this large
要比这个大间距分类器所体现的
margin view might suggest.
更成熟
And in particular, if all you're
尤其是当你使用
doing is use a large
大间距分类器的时候
margin classifier then your
你的学习算法
learning algorithms can be sensitive
会受异常点 (outlier) 的影响
to outliers, so lets just
比如我们加入
add an extra positive example
一个额外的正样本
like that shown on the screen.
在这里
If he had one example then
如果你加了这个样本
it seems as if to separate
为了将样本
data with a large margin,
用最大间距分开
maybe I'll end up learning
也许我最终
a decision boundary like that, right?
会得到一条类似这样的决策界 对么?
that is the magenta line and
就是这条粉色的线
it's really not clear that based
仅仅基于
on the single outlier based on
一个异常值
a single example and it's
仅仅基于一个样本
really not clear that it's
就将
actually a good idea to change
我的决策界
my decision boundary from the black
从这条黑线变到这条粉线
one over to the magenta one.
这实在是不明智的
So, if C, if
而如果正则化参数 C
the regularization parameter C were very
设置的非常大
large, then this is
这事实上正是
actually what SVM will do, it will
支持向量机将会做的
change the decision boundary
它将决策界
from the black to the
从黑线
magenta one but if
变到了粉线
C were reasonably small if
但是如果 C 设置的小一点
you were to use the C,
如果你将 C
not too large then you
设置的不要太大
still end up with this
则你最终会得到
black decision boundary.
这条黑线
And of course if the data were not linearly separable so if you had some positive
当然数据如果不是线性可分的
examples in here, or if
如果你在这里
you had some negative examples
有一些正样本 或者
in here then the SVM
你在这里有一些负样本
will also do the right thing.
则支持向量机也会将它们恰当分开
And so this picture of
因此
a large margin classifier that's
大间距分类器的描述
really, that's really the
真的
picture that gives better intuition
仅仅是从直观上给出了
only for the case of when the
正则化参数 C
regulations parameter C is
非常大的情形
very large, and just
同时
to remind you this corresponds
要提醒你 C 的作用
C plays a role similar to
类似于
one over Lambda, where Lambda
λ 分之一 λ 是
is the regularization parameter
我们之前使用过
we had previously. And so it's
的正则化参数
only of one over Lambda
这只是C非常大的情形
is very large or equivalently
或者等价地
if Lambda is very small that
λ 非常小的情形
you end up with things like
你最终会得到
this Magenta decision boundary, but
类似粉线这样的决策界
in practice when applying support vector machines,
但是实际上 应用支持向量机的时候
when C is not very very large
当 C 不是
like that,
非常非常大的时候
it can do a better job ignoring
它可以忽略掉一些异常点的影响
the few outliers like here. And
得到更好的决策界
also do fine and  do reasonable things
甚至当你的数据不是线性可分的时候
even if your data is not linearly separable.
支持向量机也可以给出好的结果
But when we talk about bias and variance in the context of support vector machines
我们稍后会介绍一点
which will do
支持向量机的偏差和方差
a little bit later, hopefully all
希望在那时候
of of this trade-offs involving the regularization
关于如何处理参数的这种平衡会变得
parameter will become clearer at
更加清晰
that time. So I hope
我希望
that gives some intuition about
这节课给出了一些
how this support vector machine functions as
关于为什么支持向量机
a large margin classifier that
被看做大间距分类器的直观理解
tries to separate the data with
它用最大间距将样本区分开
a large margin, technically this
尽管从技术上讲
picture of this view is true
这只有当
only when the parameter C is very large, which is
参数C是非常大的时候是真的
a useful way to think about support vector machines.
但是它对于理解支持向量机是有益的
There was one missing step in
本节课中 我们略去了一步
this video which is, why is
那就是我们在幻灯片中
it that the optimization problem we
给出的优化问题
wrote down on these
为什么会是这样的
slides, how does that actually
它是如何
lead to the large margin classifier, I
得出大间距分类器的
didn't do that in this video,
我在本节中没有讲解
in the next video I
在下一节课中
will sketch a little bit
我将略述
more of the math behind that
这些问题背后的数学原理
to explain
来解释
that separate reasoning of how
这个优化问题
the optimization problem we wrote out
是如何
results in a large margin classifier.
得到一个大间距分类器的【教育无边界字幕组】翻译: shamolvzhou 校对/审核: 所罗门捷列夫